Julian Hoover

Front End Developer

369 Molino Avenue Mill Valley, CA 94941

Phone: 415.450.5490

Email: info@brighthousemedia.org

Portfolio: https://jwho85.github.io/portfolio-website/index.html

Company: https://brighthousemedia.org/

Summary

Front End Developer with 6 years of experience working with WordPress and Hubspot. Skills include HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, React, WordPress, Salient, Divi, Elementor, Visual Composer, Gravity Forms, Yoast, WP Rocket, WPMU, HubSpot, Zapier, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, SEO, and site speed optimization.

Experience

Alaniz Marketing / Front End Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - PRESENT, NOVATO, CA

- Built over a dozen WordPress websites using Salient, Divi, Elementor, Visual Composer, Gravity Forms, Yoast, WP Rocket, WPMU, and WooCommerce
- Built over a dozen HubSpot landing pages and emails by coding templates and creating custom workflows for clients
- Followed a thorough QA process and optimized sites for desktop and mobile
- Integrated Zapier, Google Analytics, and Google Tag Manager onto sites
- Ran SEO audits using SEMrush and optimized pages in areas that were lacking
- Worked on WordPress site speed optimization using WP Rocket

Vivalon / Website Administrator

DECEMBER 2015 - AUGUST 2022, SAN RAFAEL, CA

- Built landing pages using WordPress and Elementor
- Updated the navigation and footer as needed
- Created complex forms using Gravity Forms
- Maintained theme and plugins
- Helped the marketing team with HTML and CSS issues

The Walt Disney Family Museum / Website Administrator

NOVEMBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2018, SAN FRANCISCO, CA

- Built landing pages using Drupal
- Maintained events across the site

_

Education

CareerFoundry / Web Development

2022 - 2022, ONLINE

I studied full-stack web development with a focus on HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Angular, and MERN.

College of Marin / Multimedia Studies

2011 - 2014, KENTFIELD, CA

I studied multimedia with a focus on web design, graphic design, and video.

San Francisco State University / BA in Music

2004 - 2008, SAN FRANCISCO, CA

I studied music with a focus on jazz and world music.